<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Samuel Kindylides on Samuel Kindylides</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Samuel Kindylides on Samuel Kindylides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Samuel Kindylides (license [CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/))</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>New project test : Self-sustaining aquarium</title>
      <link>/project/new-project-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/new-project-test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes a self-sustaining aquarium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic idea behind a self-sustaining aquarium is to create an aquarium which inhabitants don&#39;t need constant care to survive. You don&#39;t need to add anything to the aquarium, and you don&#39;t need to take anything out. The only outside help you need to provide is light and the addition of water from time to time. Creating perfect balance in such a restrained space is a pretty complicated feat to accomplish, requiring a lot of patience and potentially multiple attempts to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without going too much into details, here are the main components required for making such an aquarium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you&#39;ll need an aquarium. There are a lot of different types of aquariums you could use, from a small bowl to a huge fish tank. They all have pros and cons so you will have to make up your mind on what you really want to do. A small aquarium doesn&#39;t take up much space and is pretty inexpensive but is quite hard to maintain for an extended period of time and doesn&#39;t allow for a lot of diversity. A medium-sized aquarium allows for much more diversity but has a higher cost than a small one. A big fish tank adds even more diversity options but increases the cost and the room required in order to build it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is adding substrate. It is prefered to add a finer substrate as the base layer with coarser substrate above to allow your plants to settle strongly on the bottom of the aquarium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next-up is to add water. You can use tap water with dechlorinating drops or bottled spring water. If you use tap water, make sure that it has been detoxified from heavy metals by your water provider (it normally is in the vast majority of places around the world).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings us to the living part of the aquarium : algae, plants, fishes, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In smaller tanks, algae and micro-organisms are going to be the base of the food chain. But for bigger, heavier tanks you are going to need bigger plants. Plants will use the animal waste as a source of nutrients, as fertilizers. They will also reduce the amount of nitrates in the water and compete with algae, reducing blooms that give a murky, dirty look to your tank. You can choose to use a very large variety of plants in your aquarium, as different layers (the bottom of the tank, the surface, the swimming part) can house different types of plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of animals, you need primary consumers such as small flatworms, small snails, small crustaceans that will eat plants and serve as food for the primary predators of your tank, small fishes. You can also add bigger herbivorous species such as freshwater shrimps. When the food resources and the populations have increased enough and if your fish tank is big enough, you could start to add larger predatory fishes in small quantity and see how your ecosystem reacts to this new presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your aquarium got this point without any trouble, it is safe to say that you are now the proud owner of a self-sustaining mini-ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test de R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2018-09-24-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 18:36:00 -0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-09-24-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dans un document R Markdown on peut utiliser naturellement la syntaxe &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;, mais aussi du code R dans des “chunks”, comme ci-dessous pour générer un graphique (Fig. &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:pie&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;) :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;par(mar = c(0, 1, 0, 1))
pie(
  c(280, 60, 20),
  c(&amp;#39;Sky&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Sunny side of pyramid&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Shady side of pyramid&amp;#39;),
  col = c(&amp;#39;#0292D8&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#F7EA39&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#C4B632&amp;#39;),
  init.angle = -50, border = NA
)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:pie&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./post/2018-09-24-r-rmarkdown_files/figure-html/pie-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Un superbe graphique en camembert.&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Un superbe graphique en camembert.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My project</title>
      <link>/project/example-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/example-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here I describe my project using Markdown formatting...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First blog post : Test</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;actually-testing-the-different-modification-types&#34;&gt;Actually testing the different modification types.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New post : Poison dart frog</title>
      <link>/post/poison-dart-frog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/poison-dart-frog/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;colorful-but-deadly&#34;&gt;Colorful but deadly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poison dart frog is the name commonly given to a group of frogs belonging to the family &lt;strong&gt;Dendrobatidae&lt;/strong&gt;. They are mostly found in tropical rainforests like in Central and South America but many of them are threatened due to human activity and deforestation. They only measure up to a couple of centimeters in length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Dendrobatidae&lt;/strong&gt; family is composed of two sub-families, being the Colostethinae sub-family and the Dendrobatinae sub-family. Dendrobatinae frogs, on the one hand, are brightly colored and their colourful patterns are directly linked to their toxicity, making them aposematic. Aposematism is a characteristic used to warn potential predators of an animal&#39;s toxicity. On the other hand, Colostethinae frogs are cryptically colored, meaning they have a coloration that grants them a sort of camouflage. These frogs are therefore not toxic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poison dart frog gets its name from Amerindian culture where the frog&#39;s toxic secretions were used to coat the tip of blowdarts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
